I. M. Pei Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Publicity File, 1946-2012 (Box 414-443)
  Newspaper and magazine clippings, book excerpts, interviews, and some photographs; correspondence with writers, interviewers, and publishers; a bibliography of articles on Pei (1952-1983); and speaking engagement requests, arrangements, and some texts of remarks documenting the span of Pei’s architectural career. A general file focuses broadly on Pei and his work. A project file relates to specific projects undertaken by Pei and his firm. A speaking engagement file contains requests for Pei to speak and arrangements for the invitations he accepted. The texts of a few of his remarks are included. Other material relating to publicity and speaking engagements can be found in the General Correspondence, Scrapbooks, and Miscellany series.
  Arranged in three file groupings: general, projects, and speaking engagements. The general file is organized chronologically. The projects file is arranged alphabetically by name of city or country and alphabetically therein by name of project. The speaking engagements file is arranged chronologically.
  - General (Box 414)
    - 1946-1976, (9 folders) (Box 414)
    - 1977-1984, (9 folders) (Box 415)
    - 1985, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 415, Box 416)
    - 1986-1987, (3 folders) (Box 416)
    - 1988-1992 See also Container OV 11, Series of interviews, (7 folders) (Box 417)
    - 1993 See also Container OV 27, Article, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 417, Box 418)
    - 1994, (3 folders) (Box 418)
    - 1995, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 418, Box 419)
    - 1996, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 419, Box 420)
    - 1997, (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 420, Box 421)
    - 1998, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 421, Box 422)
    - 1999, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 422, Box 423)
    - 2000, (6 folders); (4 folders) (Box 423, Box 424)
    - 2001, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 424, Box 425)
    - 2002, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box 425, Box 426)
    - 2003 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_050, (6 folders) (Box 426)
    - 2004 See also Container OV 11, Color photographic portrait; Digital Files, mss83787_123_029, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 426, Box 427)
    - 2005, (3 folders) (Box 427)
    - 2006 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_026; mss83787_123_027; mss83787_123_028, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 427, Box 428)
    - 2007 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_024; mss83787_123_025, (5 folders) (Box 428, Box 429)
    - 2008 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_042, (6 folders); (8 folders) (Box 429, Box 430)
    - 2009 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_031; mss83787_123_032, (3 folders); (6 folders) (Box 430, Box 431)
    - 2010 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_030; mss83787_123_033; mss83787_123_043, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 431, Box 432)
    - 2011 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_034, (5 folders) (Box 432)
    - 2012 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_035, (2 folders) (Box 432)
  - Periodical reference guide (1952-1983), 1983 (Box 432)
  - Projects (Box 432)
    - Athens, Greece, Athens Museum of Contemporary Art, 1993 (Box 432)
    - Beijing, China (Box 432)
      - Bank of China Head Office, 2000-2002 (Box 432)
      - Fragrant Hill Hotel, 1982-1987, 1997, 2008, (4 folders) (Box 433)
    - Berlin, Germany, Deutsches Historisches Museum, 1996-2008 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_036; mss83787_123_037, (7 folders) (Box 433)
    - Beverly Hills, Calif., Creative Artists Agency Headquarters, 1989-1990 (Box 434)
    - Bilbao, Spain, Estuary Project and Emblematic Towers, 1990 (Box 434)
    - Birmingham, Ala., Kirklin Clinic, 1995 (Box 434)
    - Boston, Mass. (Box 434)
      - Christian Science Center, 1965 (Box 434)
      - John F. Kennedy Library, 1964-1966, 1973-1990, 2009 See also Container OV 11, Commemorative booklet, (3 folders) (Box 434)
      - John Hancock Tower, 1977 (Box 434)
      - Museum of Fine Arts West Wing, 1977-1983, (3 folders) (Box 434)
    - Boulder, Colo., National Center for Atmospheric Research, 1964-1967, 1985-1988 (Box 434)
    - Brooklyn, N.Y., Bedford-Stuyvesant Superblock, 1976 (Box 434)
    - Cambridge, Mass. (Box 434)
      - Cecil and Ida Green Center for the Earth Sciences, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1960-1966 (Box 434)
      - Wiesner Building, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1985-1998 (Box 434)
    - Chicago, Ill., Hyde Park Redevelopment, 1962-1965 (Box 434)
    - Cleveland, Ohio, Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, 1988-2010, (4 folders) (Box 435)
    - Columbus, Ind., Cleo Rogers Memorial Library, 1970-1971 (Box 435)
    - Dallas, Tex. (Box 435)
      - Dallas City Hall, 1976-1979 (Box 435)
      - Morton H. Myerson Symphony Center, 1982-1991, 2004, (2 folders) (Box 435)
      - One Dallas Center, 1982 (Box 435)
    - Dawhah, Qatar, Museum of Islamic Art, 2007 (Box 435)
    - Denver, Colo., various projects, 1953-1960, 1980 (Box 435)
    - Des Moines, Iowa, Des Moines Art Center addition, 1968-1969, 1998 (Box 435)
    - Fort Worth, Tex., Tandy House, 1970-1974 (Box 435)
    - Hong Kong (Box 435)
      - Bank of China Tower, 1984-1991, 2006 See also Container OV 11, Wall calendar, (2 folders) (Box 435, Box 436)
      - Sunning Plaza, 1982 (Box 436)
    - Honolulu, Hawaii, Metropolitan Tower, 1961 (Box 436)
    - Houston, Tex., Texas Commerce Tower, 1981-1983 (Box 436)
    - Ithaca, N.Y., Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, Cornell University 1973-1977 (Box 436)
    - Katonah, N.Y., Pei residence, 1961-1963 (Box 436)
    - La Rochefoucauld, France, Château de la Rochefoucauld, 1999 (Box 436)
    - Lincoln, Nebr., National Bank of Commerce, 1978 (Box 436)
    - Long Island, N.Y. (Box 436)
      - Franklin National Bank, circa 1966 (Box 436)
      - Roosevelt Field, 1955-1957 (Box 436)
    - Los Angeles, Calif., Ronald Reagan UCLA Medical Center, 1997-2007 (Box 436)
    - Luxembourg, Luxembourg, Musée d'Art Moderne Grand-Duc Jean, 1995-2007, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 436, Box 437)
    - Marin County, Calif., Buck Institute for Age Research, 1999 (Box 437)
    - Montreal, Canada, Place Ville Marie, 1960-1965, 2002 (Box 437)
    - New York, N.Y. (Box 437)
      - 11 Sutton Place, Pei residence, 1988 (Box 437)
      - 383 Madison Ave., William Zeckendorf office, 1952 (Box 437)
      - Four Seasons Hotel renovation, 1993-2007 (Box 437)
      - Helix Apartment, 1950 (Box 437)
      - Jacob K. Javits Convention Center, 1980-1986 (Box 437)
      - Kips Bay Plaza, 1960-1964 (Box 437)
      - Mount Sinai Medical Center, 1985 (Box 437)
      - National Airlines Terminal, John F. Kennedy International Airport, 1971 (Box 437)
      - San Remo Towers, 1987 (Box 438)
      - Union Terminal, New York International Airport, 1960 (Box 438)
      - University Village and Plaza, New York University, 1966-1968 (Box 438)
    - Oklahoma City, Okla., Central Business District Plan, circa 1963-1964 (Box 438)
    - Paris, Le Grand Louvre (Box 438)
      - 1983-1988, (11 folders) (Box 438)
      - 1989-2006, (11 folders) (Box 439)
    - Philadelphia, Pa., Society Hill, 1958-1965, 2006 (Box 440)
    - Pittsburgh, Pa., Washington Plaza, 1964 (Box 440)
    - Portland, Maine, Museum of Art, 1982-1983 (Box 440)
    - Princeton, N.J., Laura Spelman Rockefeller Halls, Princeton University, 1976 (Box 440)
    - San Francisco, Calif., Ferry Building, 1981 (Box 440)
    - Shanghai, China, Hua Tung Christian University, 1952 (Box 440)
    - Shiga, Japan (Box 440)
      - Miho Museum (Box 440)
        - 1996-1998 See also Container OV 11, Marked-up galley proof of commemorative booklet, (6 folders) (Box 440)
        - 1999-2002 See also Container OV 42, Wall calendars (Box 441)
      - Shinji Shumeikai Bell Tower, 1991 (Box 441)
    - Singapore (Box 441)
      - Oversea-Chinese Banking Corp. Centre, 1976-1983 (Box 441)
      - Raffles City, 1980-1986 (Box 441)
    - Suzhou Shi, China (Box 441)
      - Lion Grove Garden, 1988, 2000 (Box 441)
      - Suzhou Museum, 2003-2007, (2 folders) (Box 441)
    - Syracuse, N.Y. (Box 441)
      - Everson Museum of Art, 1962-2000 (Box 441)
      - S. I. Newhouse School of Public Communications Center, Syracuse University, 1965 (Box 441)
    - T'ai-chung shih, Taiwan, Luce Memorial Chapel, Tunghai University, 1957-1964 (Box 441)
    - Toronto, Canada, Commerce Court, Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce, 1994-1998 (Box 441)
    - Various locations, Federal Aviation Administration air traffic control towers, 1963 (Box 441)
    - Wallingford, Conn., Paul Mellon Center for the Arts, Choate Rosemary Hall, 1973, 1983 (Box 441)
    - Washington, D.C. (Box 441)
      - East Building of the National Gallery of Art (Box 441)
        - 1971-1978, (3 folders) (Box 441)
        - 1978-2002, (2 folders) (Box 442)
      - Embassy of the People's Republic of China, 2006-2008 (Box 442)
      - Southwest Washington Redevelopment Plan, 1963 (Box 442)
      - Town Center Plaza, 1961 (Box 442)
      - United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, 1987 (Box 442)
    - Wilmington, Del., Wilmington Tower, 1970 (Box 442)
    - Wiltshire, England, Oare Pavilion, 2003-2005 (Box 442)
  - Speaking engagements (Box 442)
    - 1979-1997, (8 folders) (Box 442)
    - 1998-2012 See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_038, (10 folders) (Box 443)
- Scrapooks, 1944-2006 (Box 444-460)
  Newspaper and magazine clippings, interviews, correspondence, programs, certificates, awards, honorary degrees, invitations, brochures, photographs, a sketch by Pei, press releases, and some texts of remarks from more than one hundred scrapbooks. Forty-five general volumes span the years 1944-2004 and document Pei’s career largely through newspaper and magazine clippings. Other volumes focus on specific projects including the Dallas City Hall, East Building of the National Gallery of Art, Grand Louvre, John F. Kennedy Library, and the Miho Museum. Four volumes contain published interviews with Pei. Six volumes house memorabilia, and seven volumes contain special letters.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and therein by volume number.
  - Dallas City Hall, Dallas, Tex., opening, 1978 (Box 444)
  - East Building of the National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C., 1978 (Box 444)
  - General (Box 444)
    - Vols. 1-3, 1944-1965, (7 folders) (Box 444)
    - Vol. 4 (Box 444)
      - 1965-1967, Oct., (2 folders) (Box 444)
      - 1967, Nov.-Dec. (Box 445)
    - Vols. 5-9, 1968-1978, (11 folders) (Box 445)
    - Vols. 10-14, 1978, (12 folders) (Box 446)
    - Vols. 15-20, 1978-1979, (14 folders) (Box 447)
    - Vols. 21-23, 1978-1984, (12 folders) (Box 448)
    - Vols. 24-28, 1983-1985, (13 folders) (Box 449)
    - Vols. 29-35, 1985-1989, (13 folders) (Box 450)
    - Vols. 36-42, 1989-1994, (15 folders) (Box 451)
    - Vols. 43-45, 1995-2004, (6 folders) (Box 452)
  - Le Grand Louvre, Paris, France (Box 452)
    - Vols. 1-6, 1951, 1981-1984, June, (11 folders) (Box 452)
    - Vols. 7-15, 1984, July-1985, (18 folders) (Box 453)
    - Vols. 16-24, 1986, 1988, Sept., (16 folders) (Box 454)
    - Vols. 25-30, 1988, Oct.-1989, May, (11 folders) (Box 455)
    - Vols. 31-34, 1989, June-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 456)
  - Interviews (Box 456)
    - Vols. 1-3, 1948-1988, (4 folders) (Box 456)
    - Vol. 4, 1986-1989 (Box 457)
  - John F. Kennedy Library, Boston, Mass, vols. 1-7, 1964-1981, 1988-1989, (7 folders) (Box 457)
  - Memorabilia (Box 458)
    - Vols. 1-3, 1960-1986, (11 folders) (Box 458)
    - Vol. 4 (Box 458)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 458)
      - 1988 (Box 459)
    - Vols. 5-6, 1989-2006, (4 folders) (Box 459)
  - Miho Museum, Shiga, Japan, vols. 1-2, 1987-1998, (3 folders) (Box 459)
  - Special letters (Box 459)
    - Vol. 1, 1946-1980 (Box 459)
    - Vol. 2-7, 1979-2006, undated, (7 folders) (Box 460)
- Miscellany, 1920-2014 (Box 461-505)
  Certificates, citations, biographical files, itineraries, correspondence, invitations, appointment calendars, speeches, press releases, clippings, notes, and photographs documenting Pei’s professional and personal life. Largely consists of documentation related to awards, honorary degrees, architectural registrations, education, exhibitions, competitions, and travel records.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or material type.
  - Appointment calendars (Box 461)
    - 1955-1958, (4 folders) (Box 461)
    - 1959-1963, (5 folders) (Box 462)
    - 1964-1968, (5 folders) (Box 463)
    - 1969-1973, (5 folders) (Box 464)
    - 1974-1977, (4 folders) (Box 465)
    - 1978-1981, (4 folders) (Box 466)
    - 1982-1984, (3 folders) (Box 467)
    - 1985-1987, (3 folders) (Box 468)
    - 1988, (2 folders) (Box 469)
    - 1989, (1 folder) (Box 469, Box 470)
    - 1990, (2 folders) (Box 470)
    - 1991, (1 folder) (Box 470, Box 471)
    - 1992-1993, (3 folders) (Box 471)
    - 1994-1996, (3 folders) (Box 472)
    - 1997-2002, (6 folders) (Box 473)
    - 2003-2010, (8 folders) (Box 474)
    - 2011-2012, (2 folders) (Box 475)
  - Appointment and telephone logs (Box 475)
    - 1990-1991, (3 folders) (Box 475)
    - 1992-1995, (6 folders) (Box 476)
    - 1996, (1 folder) (Box 476, Box 477)
    - 1997-2000, (8 folders) (Box 477)
    - 2001-2004, (8 folders) (Box 478)
    - 2005-2006, (4 folders) (Box 479)
  - Architectural registration lists, 1988-1997 (Box 479)
  - Architectural registrations (Box 479)
    - France, 1984, 1994-2009 (Box 479)
    - Hong Kong, 1978-1979 (Box 479)
    - National Council of Architectural Registration Boards, 1956, 1964, 1988-1998 (Box 479)
    - Singapore, 1974-1991, 2006 See also Container OV 12, Certificate of registration (Box 479)
    - United Kingdom, 1974, 1984-1991 (Box 479)
    - United States (Box 479)
      - Alabama-Florida, 1957-1964, 1974-2002 See also Container OV 12, Certificates of registration (Box 479)
      - Georgia-Michigan, 1960-1975, 1981-2005 See also Container OV 12, Certificates of registration (Box 479)
      - Missouri-North Carolina, 1954-1955, 1971-1974, 1982-2003 See also Container OV 12, Certificates of registration (Box 479)
      - Ohio-Tennessee, 1959-1965, 1974-1997 See also Container OV 12, Certificates of registration (Box 480)
      - Texas-Wisconsin, 1966-1974, 1984-1994 See also Container OV 12, Certificates of registration (Box 480)
  - Awards and honors (Box 480)
    - 1960s, miscellaneous awards and honors See also Containers OV 12-OV 13, Award certificates (Box 480)
    - 1961, Arnold Brunner Award, National Institute of Arts and Letters, New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 13, Award certificate (Box 480)
    - 1963 (Box 480)
      - Membership, National Institute of Arts and Letters, New York, N.Y. (Box 480)
      - People’s Architect, Rice University, Houston, Tex. (Box 480)
    - 1966 (Box 480)
      - Harleston Parker Medal, Boston Society of Architects, Boston, Mass. (Box 480)
      - Membership, National Council on the Humanities, Washington, D.C. See also Container OV 27, Certificate of appointment (Box 480)
    - 1967, Albert S. Bard Citation, Citizens Union of the City of New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 13, Citation (Box 480)
    - 1968, Architectural Firm Award, American Institute of Architects, Washington, D.C. (awarded to I. M. Pei & Partners) (Box 480)
    - 1970, Golden Door Award, International Institute of Boston, Boston, Mass. (Box 480)
    - 1973, "For New York" Award, City Club of New York, New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 13, Award certificate (Box 480)
    - 1975, Membership, Royal Institute of British Architects, London, England See also Container OV 13, Membership certificate (Box 480)
    - 1976, Thomas Jefferson Memorial Medal, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Va. (Box 480)
    - 1978, Man of the Year award, Chinatown Planning Council, New York, N.Y. (Box 480)
    - 1978-1979, Gold Medal, American Institute of Architects, New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 13, Citation for distinguished achievement, and Container OV 43, Certificate for the Gold Medal, (1 folder) (Box 480, Box 481)
    - 1980s, miscellaneous awards and honors See also Containers OV 13 and OV 27, Certificates (Box 481)
    - 1981 (Box 481)
      - Creative Arts Award, Brandeis University, Waltham, Mass. (awarded to I. M. Pei & Partners) (Box 481)
      - Gold Medal of Honor, Alpha Rho Chi, national professional architecture fraternity (Box 481)
      - Gold Medal of Honor, National Arts Club, New York, N.Y. (Box 481)
      - La Grande Medaille d’Or, l’Académie d’architecture, Paris, France (Box 481)
      - Mayor’s Award of Honor for Arts and Culture, City of New York, New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 27, Certificate (Box 481)
    - 1982, Lord & Taylor Rose Award, Lord & Taylor, New York, N.Y. (Box 481)
    - 1983-1984, Pritzker Architecture Prize, Hyatt Foundation, Chicago, Ill., (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 481, Box 482)
    - 1984 (Box 482)
      - Honor Award, American Institute of Architects, Washington, D.C. (Box 482)
      - Membre associe, Académie des beaux-arts, Institut de France, Paris, France, (4 folders) (Box 482)
    - 1985 (Box 482)
      - Commandeur l’Ordre des arts et des lettres, France (Box 482)
      - Eugene McDermott Award, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 482)
      - Personnalité de l'année, Distinction Internationale Créée en 1970, Beaux Arts, Paris, France See also Container OV 27, Certificate (Box 482)
    - 1985-1986, honorary professorship, Tongji University, Shanghai, China (Box 483)
    - 1986 (Box 483)
      - Medal of Liberty, United States, (2 folders) (Box 483)
      - Raffles City appreciation certificate, Singapore (Box 483)
    - 1987, Asian American Freedom Award, Asian Americans for Community Involvement, San Jose, Calif. (Box 483)
    - 1988 (Box 483)
      - Chevalier de la Légion d’honneur, France (Box 483)
      - National Medal of Art, United States (Box 483)
    - 1989 (Box 483)
      - Design Award for Pyramide du Louvre, European Convention for Constructional Steelwork (Box 483)
      - Praemium Imperiale, Fujisankei Communications Group, Japan (Box 483)
    - 1990 (Box 483)
      - Citation, Engineering News-Record, New York, N.Y. (Box 483)
      - Gold Medal, University of California, Los Angeles (Box 483)
      - Grands Projets Parisiens Prize, Le Moniteur, Paris, France (Box 483)
    - 1991 (Box 483)
      - Award for Excellence, Colbert Foundation, New York, N.Y. (Box 483)
      - Excellence 2000 Award, Organization of Chinese American Women and United States Pan Asian American Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C. (Box 483)
      - R. S. Reynolds Memorial Award, American Institute of Architects, Washington, D.C. See also Container OV 27, Award certificate (Box 483)
    - 1992 (Box 483)
      - Lifetime Achievement Award, New York Society of Architects, New York, N.Y. (Box 483)
      - Presidential Medal of Freedom, United States (Box 483)
    - 1993 (Box 483)
      - “I. M. Pei Day” Proclamation, Office of the Mayor, New York, N.Y.; Lifetime achievement citation, Office of the President, Borough of Manhattan, New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 13, Certificate (Box 484)
      - Lifetime Achievement Award, Harvard Graduate School of Design, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 484)
    - 1994 (Box 484)
      - Gold Award, Architectural Society of China, Beijing, China (Box 484)
      - Governor’s Arts Award, New York (Box 484)
      - Jerusalem Prize for Arts and Letters, Friends of Bezalel Academy of Arts and Design, New York, N.Y. See also Container OV 27, Award certificate (Box 484)
      - Medal of Arts Award, National Council on the Arts, Washington, D.C. (Box 484)
    - 1995, Fellows Award, New York State Association of Architects, Albany, N.Y. See also Container OV 16, Award certificate (Box 484)
    - 1996 (Box 484)
      - China International Science and Technical Cooperation Prize, State Committee of Science and Technology of the People’s Republic of China (Box 484)
      - Foreign member, Chinese Academy of Engineering, Beijing, China (Box 484)
      - Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis Medal, Municipal Art Society, New York, N.Y. (Box 484)
      - Man of the Year Award, GQ, New York, N.Y. (Box 484)
      - Premio Internazionale Novecento La Rosa D’Oro, Novecento, Palermo, Italy (Box 484)
      - President’s Award, American Institute of Architects New York Chapter, New York, N.Y. (Box 484)
    - 1997 (Box 484)
      - Declined awards and honors (Box 484)
      - Honorary Consultancy in Chinese Vernacular Architecture, Jiangsu Science and Technology Publishing House, Zhenjiang, China (Box 485)
      - Independent Award, Brown University, Providence, R.I. (Box 485)
      - Membre de l’Académie d’architecture de France, Paris, France (Box 485)
    - 1998 (Box 485)
      - Edward MacDowell Medal, MacDowell Colony, Peterborough, N.H. (Box 485)
      - Gold Dragon Award, Hong Kong Literature and Artists Association, Kowloon, Hong Kong (Box 485)
      - Hiroba Prize (for Miho Museum), Kinki Architect Council, Japan (Box 485)
      - Pioneer Award, Organization of Chinese Americans, Washington, D.C. (Box 485)
      - Premio Internazionale Novecento La Rosa d'Oro (Box 485)
    - 1999 (Box 485)
      - BZ-Kulturpreis, BZ, Berlin, Germany (Box 485)
      - Certificate of Honor, Structural Engineers Association of Illinois, Chicago, Ill. (Box 485)
      - Cultural Laureate, Historic Landmark Preservation Center, New York, N.Y. (Box 485)
      - Diamond Award for Excellence in Bridge Engineering (for Miho Museum bridge, Shiga, Japan), New York Association of Consulting Engineers, New York, N.Y. (Box 485)
      - Honorary Membership, American Institute of Architects, Hong Kong Chapter, Hong Kong See also Container OV 13, Honorary membership certificate (Box 485)
    - 2000 (Box 485)
      - Frank Annunzio Award (finalist), Christopher Columbus Fellowship Foundation, Auburn, N.Y. (Box 485)
      - Guest of Honor, Art Commission of the City of New York, N.Y. (Box 485)
      - Living Legend Award, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. (Box 485)
    - 2001, Thomas Jefferson Medal, American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Pa. (Box 485)
    - 2002, Outstanding Structure Award (for Miho Museum bridge, Shigaraki, Japan), International Association for Bridge and Structural Engineering, Zurich, Switzerland (Box 485)
    - 2003 (Box 485)
      - National Design Award for Lifetime Achievement, Smithsonian Institution, Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum, New York, N.Y. (Box 485)
      - Henry C. Turner Prize for Innovation in Construction Technology, National Building Museum, Washington, D.C. See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_012 (Box 485)
    - 2003-2012, declined awards and honors (Box 486)
    - 2004 (Box 486)
      - Laurea Honoris Causa, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_010; mss83787_123_011 (Box 486)
      - Peopling of America Award, Statue of Liberty-Ellis Island Foundation, New York, N.Y. See also Digital Files, mss83787_123_008 (Box 486)
      - Twenty-five Year Award (for East Wing, National Gallery of Art), American Institute of Architects, Washington, D.C. (Box 486)
    - 2005 (Box 486)
      - Deutscher Natursteinpreis, Deutsches Historisches Museum, Berlin, Germany (Box 486)
      - Georgian Award (for Oare Pavilion, Wiltshire, England), Georgian Group, London, England (Box 486)
    - 2006 (Box 486)
      - Miscellaneous awards and honors (Box 486)
      - Orient und Okzident Preis, Akaddemie der Wissenschaften und der Literatur, Mainz, Germany (Box 486)
    - 2008, Lifetime Achievement Award, Museum of Chinese in America, New York, N.Y. (Box 486)
    - 2009 (Box 486)
      - Reconocimiento, University of Guadalajara, Mexico (Box 486)
      - New York City 400, Museum of the City of New York, New York, N.Y. (Box 486)
    - 2010 (Box 486)
      - Professorship, I. M. Pei Chair in Islamic Art and Architecture, University of Oxford, England, endowed by the Qatar Foundation, Dawhah, Qatar (Box 486)